Andrew Tio

andrewmtio@gmail.com| (415)992-2092 https://github.com/andrewteeoh | http://andrewtio.com/

SUMMARY

Front-end web developer focused on creating highly engaging, responsive sites. Experience working in a service-oriented architecture. Learns and adapts quickly, with a working knowledge of agile development. Strives to produce high quality code by participating in code reviews with peers. Works well with others and enjoys a constructive and collaborative work environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, NodeJS, PHP Tools: Git, npm, Gulp, SVN

Frameworks: Express, jQuery, Angular 1.2, Leaflet

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

March 2013 - present

Blizzard Entertainment, San Francisco, CA

- Participated in candidate resume reviews and interviews
- Provided consistent content updates to the Heroes of the Storm game site (Java/Spring) in the form of interactive Battleground maps (Leaflet), hero pages (Angular), and promotional event pages, increasing user engagement
- Pioneered Blizzard's first responsive game site with Heroes of the Storm in NodeJS using Express framework
- Updated Blizzcon.com (Java/Spring) attendance and eSports information leading up to BlizzCon 2014
- Supported Hearthstone iOS/Android and expansion launches through periodic site updates
- Built StarCraft II World Championship Series website (Ruby/Sinatra) with a focus on executing development of professional StarCraft II player pages

Web Developer

February 2011 - February 2013

IGN Entertainment, San Francisco, CA

- Rebuilt video player page on new Zend Framework 2 platform within a rigid time frame to meet sponsorship demands, reducing page load times by 30%
- Assisted in schema design for IGN's new core game database and led front-end migration of game and movie pages, improving maintainability and visual appeal
- Cultivated developer relations with 3rd party partner Disgus to implement modern commenting system across all media content on IGN, increasing user engagement
- Approved pull requests and participated in code reviews
- Built prototype TV channel for Hack Week 2012, winning Best in Show award
- Developed shareable skill and loadout builder for various game genres for Hack Week October 2011, winning Mega Franchise category

Junior Web Developer

April 2010 - February 2011

IGN Entertainment, San Francisco, CA

- Led front-end effort to update video player and video gallery pages to Zend Framework platform, introducing dynamic recirculation modules and improving video discovery
- Developed specs and requirements with video API engineer

Engineering Intern

November 2009 - April 2010

IGN Entertainment, San Francisco, CA

- Led efforts to develop site search for IGN.com and affiliated sites on Zend Framework based front-end platform, laying front-end standards groundwork for future development
- Teamed up with a small group of engineers to revamp look and feel of IGN.com for 2010 within a tight deadline

EDUCATION

University of Southern California Los Angeles, CA

May 2009

Viterbi School of Engineering

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering/Computer Science, GPA: 3.38

Minor: Video Game Design and Management